适应
Adapt.
那是人类的本能 对吧
That's what humans do, isn't it?
我们的大优势
Our great leg up.
我们摸爬滚打
We roll.
我们见招拆招
We hack.
咬紧牙关 随机应变
Knuckle down and change.
雪国列车也是一种适应
Even Snowpiercer is an adaptation.
威尔福德就是如此
That was classic Wilford.
世界冰封时
While the world froze
其他巨富都想在地堡里躲避末日
and the other mega-rich tried to hole up in bunkers
或是上传他们的意识
or upload their consciousness,
威尔福德先生却翻出了他的旧火车
Mr. Wilford dusted off his train set.
雪国列车是他的系统
Snowpiercer is His system.
系统抗拒改变
Systems resist change,
哪怕没有缔造者的干预
even without their maker.
我只是个科学家
I'm just a scientist.
我是来拯救世界 不是改变它的
I'm here to save the world, not change it.
我知道我们的生存机会渺茫
I know our chances of surviving are slim at best.
而对此 我也只能
All I can do about that
在雪国列车上制造片刻的幸福
is provide small moments of happiness on Snowpiercer,
在这1001节车厢里
1,001 cars long.
雪国列车
第一季 第四集
怎么
Yeah?
我就知道还醒着
I knew you'd be up.
劳者无休
No rest for the weary.
怎么了
What's up?
我需要你照顾好自己 梅
I need you to take care of yourself, Mel.
你可不能病倒
We can't afford you getting sick.
供给链的问题越来越严重
There's mounting supply-chain issues,
你现在还要自己侦办谋杀案吗
and now you're taking this murder investigation on your own?
多谢你担心
I appreciate your concern.
真的
I do.
还有别的事吗
Anything else?
有
Yes.
我希望你去求助
I want you to ask for help.
帮帮我
Help.
莱顿 醒醒
Layton, wake up.
-我们需要你 -发生了什么
- We need you. - What happened?
你会看到的
You'll see.
谢谢
Thank you.
你想到甲烷短缺的
So, have you thought of a workaround
解决办法了吗
for the methane shortage?
嗯
Yep.
山羊屁
Goat farts.
很好
Very good.
麻省理工学院
MIT.
我就知道没白上
I knew it would pay off.
梅兰妮·卡维尔
Melanie Cavill.
我不怕被人看到在一起
I'm not afraid to be seen together.
你只是早上不想跟我一起去上班
You just don't want to walk to work with me in the morning?
珍珠 关于我的传闻现在够多了
Jinju, there's enough track talk about me as it is.
你必须挺身而出 宝贝
Hey, you got to step up for this, babe.
我刚刚不都挺身了吗
Isn't that what I just did?
是吗
Oh, you did, huh?
我会的 但...
And I will. I just...
给我点时间
Give me a minute.
三等厢人对于跟前车厢的人约会很别扭
Thirdies are weird about dating uptrain.
是前车厢还是后车厢有什么不同
What's the difference whether it's uptrain or downtrain?
你是二等厢的
You're from Second.
你是身处特权才会这么想
You have the privilege of seeing it that way.
宝贝 我知道你不为之所动
Okay, baby, I know you're not enticed by all this
因为你来自底特律
'cause you're from Detroit...
我来自旧金山
I'm from San Francisco.
这些地方都消失了
Those places are gone,
但现在重新开始的担子落在了我们肩上
but now it's up to us to start over.
农业员
Agricultural Officer.
妮基·吉奈特死了
Nikki Genet is dead.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我知道你有多在乎她
I know how much you cared for her.
好了 别哭了
Okay, stop now.
别哭了 亨利
Stop it, Henry.
我要给你个机会向威尔福德先生赎罪
I'm gonna give you a chance to make things right with Mr. Wilford.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我想让你去拿一台轮床和一些床单
I want you to go get a gurney and some sheets.
别让任何人看到她
Don't let anyone see her.
我们需要验尸数据
We need postmortem data.
你知道我要让你做什么吗
Do you understand what I'm asking you?
知道
Yes.
你会为我去做吗 亨利
Will you do that for me, Henry?
谢谢你
Thank you.
你去哪了
Where were you?
我跟你说了一个头等厢杀手的长相
I gave you a description of a First Class killer.
你又做了什么
What did you do with it?
我是想等到早晨
I was waiting till morning.
头等厢的人就能等到早上
First waits till morning.
她死了 杀手却还能吃到培根鸡蛋
She's dead -- our killer gets his bacon and eggs.
闭嘴 莱顿 我们都辜负了她
Shut up, Layton. We all failed her.
边境关闭了
The border's closed.
我刚从二等厢过来
I just came from Second.
搏击赛开始之后就关了
It's been closed since the fight.
杀手来自头等厢
The killer's from First.
如果他跟着你 他提前离开了搏击赛
If he followed you, he left the fight early.
没时间去前厢
No time to get uptrain.
那么他还在三等厢
Then he's still in Third.
怎么样
How we doin'?
换到早餐部来了
Switching to breakfast.
列车一圈圈走着
'Round and 'round she goes.
你想喝最后一瓶"铁路工啤酒"吗
You want one last Railman's?
不用了
Nah.
你知道他们还要把边境关多久吗
Any word how long they're keeping that damn border closed?
如果他们想的话 关一晚上都行
They'll close it all night if they want.
搏击赛一片混乱
That fight was a mess.
你来自哪里
Where you from?
二等厢
Second?
是的
Yeah.
这些是头等舱的酒水代币
Hey, these are First Class booze tokens.
谢谢
I mean... thanks.
前厢有多少人
Alright, how many men do you have uptrain?
很多
We've got plenty.
从车尾派一支搜索队到前厢
Okay, send a sweep team uptrain from the Tail.
别看了 小子
Eyes up, son.
接下来交给我们
We've got it from here.
莱顿先生不必看到这个 对吗
Mr. Layton doesn't really need to see this, does he?
他们甚至不知道自己在找谁
They don't even know who they're chasing.
我需要去头等厢
I need to go to First.
他不能踏入头等厢一步
He doesn't set one foot in First.
他听从威尔福德先生的命令
He does whatever Mr. Wilford wants.
对吗
Yes?
把所有去观看了搏击赛的头等厢乘客都叫醒
Let's get every First Class passenger that was at the fight out of bed.
这会很不受欢迎
That will not be popular.
受欢迎
Popular?
你们这有个连环杀人犯
You people have a serial killer --
低调点 好吗
Tone it down, would you?
我得知道搜索开始了
I need to know that the search is underway,
然后你和我去头等厢
and then you and I will go to First.
你要等威尔福德先生同意
You have to clear that with Mr. Wilford,
还是你能决定
or is that your call?
等你准备好 我要跟她谈谈
When you're ready, I'll be talking to her.
我的司闸员会从这开始工作
Alright, my Brakemen will work down from here.
我们打开每扇门 检查所有橱柜
We'll open every door. We'll check every cupboard.
然后去中部的农业区和我的人汇合
And meet my men in the middle at Ag-Sec.
从车尾派一支搜索队到前厢
Start a sweep team uptrain from the Tail, then.
然后我们检查所有...
From there, we will review all...
那附属列车呢
What about the subtrain?
还是禁止非必要人员进入
It's still closed to nonessential personnel.
我还是会派一支巡逻队过去
I'll put another patrol down there anyway.
他没被停职吗
He's not suspended?
我们人手不够 需要所有人
We're shorthanded. We need every man we've got.
-他在走私克洛诺 -他是你的搭档
- He was slinging Kroney. - He's your partner.
现在和好 晚点和好 随便你
Work it out now. Work it out later.
总之要做好你的工作 去吧
Just do your freakin' job. Go.
请节哀
I'm sorry for your loss.
如果凶手是头等厢的人
If the killer's from First,
那你只能调查到这了
they'll only let you get so far,
妮基将永远讨不回公道
and there won't be any justice for Nikki.
三等厢的人会怎么想
How's Third gonna take that?
两个受害者都出自那里
Both victims are theirs.
那就要拭目以待了 警探
Oh, that remains to be seen, Detective.
既然我知道你在这是做什么的了
Now that I got a sense of what you do here,
我想着你能分享下你的想法
I thought you might have a take on it.
你熟悉大家 高低贵贱都有
You know people, high and low.
你知道他们的秘密
You know their secrets.
严格保密
Strict confidentiality.
这点在夜车里有保障
It's assured in the Nightcar.
我欣赏这点
I appreciate that.
梅兰妮·卡维尔跟你聊过吗
Melanie Cavill ever have a session?
就算答案是肯定的
That would be confidential --
那也是保密信息
if the answer wasn't no.
她从未那样暴露过自己
She's never shown herself like that.
也许现在她必须如此了
Maybe now she'll have to.
你觉得妮基的死可能成为催化剂吗
Think Nikki's death could be a catalyst?
什么的催化剂
Catalyst for what?
据我所知 三等厢的工人们都受够了
From what I hear, a lot of workers in Third are pretty fed up.
你得步步为营 警探
You need to step carefully, Detective.
但我们很多人确实想改变
But many of us do want change.
我们要叫醒头等厢了
We're waking First.
奥德丽 我保证会尽全力
Audrey, I promise I'll do everything I can --
别废话了 梅兰妮
Cut the shit, Melanie.
我支持你 警探
You have my support, Detective.
我会控制附属列车
I'm holding the subtrain.
列车后方没多少人相信当权者
Not a lot of downtrain faith that the powers that be
真的想破这起案子
actually want to solve this thing
因为嫌犯是头等厢的人
now that the suspect's from First.
我想破
I want it solved.
不管凶手来自哪个车厢
And it doesn't matter which Class the suspect is from.
我们走
Let's go.
我从没见过蓝色芯片
I've never seen a blue chip before.
可能是头等厢的 开各种车门
Could be First Class, open heaps of doors.
莱顿说 "我们之间只隔了几扇门"
Layton said, "It's only doors between us."
你不能用芯片走出车尾
You can't just chip out of the Tail.
对 但可以离开清洁小队
No, but someone could chip out of Sanitation crew.
休息室
Ah, the break room.
那里有扇带键盘的门
There's that door with the key pad.
他们认为我们不能用
They think we can't use it.
你在那里藏了物资 对吧
You've been stashing supplies there, right?
是的 我们当班时搜索来的东西
Yeah. Things we scrounge on shift.
-有衣服吗 -有
- Any clothes? - Yeah.
好 如果我们能让人进入走廊 然后呢
Okay, so, if we get someone in the corridors, then what?
我们和阿斯特丽德取得联系
We make contact with Astrid.
大伙 自从她第一年出去当学徒
Since she apprenticed out in the first year,
我们有过几次她的消息 两次吗
guys, we've heard from her, what, twice?
阿斯特丽德还是我们的一员
Astrid's still one of us.
她在这里有人
She's got people here.
要是她能找到莱顿 我们就能和他建立联系
If she can find Layton, we can set up communication with him.
把芯片给我
Give me the chip.
我今晚试试
I'll try tonight.
约翰 你是一头雄狮
John, you're a lion.
他们在前列车厢不常看到车尾女人
They don't see Tailie women uptrain.
我混进去的几率更高
I've got a better chance of blending in.
这是真的
It's true.
这是我们拿到的唯一一把钥匙
This is the only key we've ever had.
清洁
Sanitation!
你朋友呢
Hey, what happened to your friend?
他病得太重没法工作 长官
Uh, he's too sick to work, sir.
好的
Okay.
快点 这边
Come on. This way.
衣服脱掉
Strip.
这不人道
It's inhuman.
你这是在逗我吧
You got to be kidding me.
艺术现在属于头等厢吗
Art belongs to First now?
这帮人先把大地烤焦 再将其冰封
These people broiled the Earth, then they froze her,
现在又把战利品挂在他们的墙上
and now they hang the spoils on their walls.
莱顿 我出生在宾州东部的泥泞农场上
Layton, I was a born on a dirt farm in Eastern Pennsylvania.
我白手起家
I came from nothing.
我对阶级概念略知一二
I know a thing or two about class.
你看到这一切时感受到的愤怒
That anger that you feel when you look at all of this?
是合理的
It's justified.
我们要利用它
Let's use it.
不论凶手是谁
Whoever the killer is,
头等厢都会保护自己人
First is going to protect their own,
你就做他们最可怕的车尾噩梦
so you be their worst nightmare from the Tail.
其他交给我
I'll do the rest.
车尾人
Tailie.
好了 先说两件事
Alright, two things first.
我不在乎你们是谁
I don't give a shit who you are,
还有这里有人喜欢
and somebody up here has got a thing
切掉三等厢乘客的老二
for chopping off Third Class dicks.
-听着 -我在听呢
- Now, look-- - Yeah, I'm looking.
是这样的
Here's the thing.
露丝
Ruth.
去看搏击的人没到齐
I don't see everybody who was at the fight.
所有人都在这儿了
This is everybody.
梅兰妮 这太荒唐了
Melanie, this is ridiculous.
头等厢还没人被定过罪
No one from First Class has ever been charged with a crime.
这你得感谢她
You should thank her for that.
她严守边境 把乌合之众拒之门外
She keeps the borders tight, she keeps the rabble at bay,
让头等厢凌驾于法律之上
and she keeps First Class above the law.
但威尔福德先生这次行事不同往常
But Mr. Wilford's doing things differently this time.
是不是这样
Isn't that right?
是的
Yes.
好了
Now...
保镖在哪里
...where are the bodyguards?
好吧 那我换种方式
Alright, let me try this a different way.
你在车尾断了多少只手臂
How many arms did you take in the Tail?
14只 如果有人数了的话
14, if anyone's counting.
那么 保镖在哪里
So, where are the bodyguards?
不是我找佣人来的
I didn't invite the help.
埃里克昨晚没有回家
Erik didn't come home last night.
他没回吗
He didn't?
是的
No.
他要求提前离开搏击之夜
He asked to leave the fight early,
当我们回来时 他不在这里
and when we came back, he wasn't here.
你知道他不见了 但却没有告诉我们
You knew he was missing and you didn't tell us?
告诉罗切 埃里克是嫌疑犯
Tell Roche Erik's a suspect.
他身上还带着枪
He has his gun, too.
-小莱 -小莱
- LJ. - LJ.
怎么了
What?
我昨晚看到他带着枪了
I saw he had it with him last night.
他还有枪吗
He has his gun?
雪国列车上不允许持枪
There are no guns allowed on the Snowpiercer.
我们的保安是可以携带随身武器的
Our security was allowed to keep their sidearm.
我们其他人却被没收武器来确保你们的安全
The rest of us were disarmed to keep you safe.
我要去看一下埃里克的住处
I'm gonna need to see Erik's quarters.
这个人不能进入我们的车厢
This man is not entering our carriage.
要把这个人带进头等厢吗
Bringing this man into First?
这从来没发生过
This is unprecedented.
我代表这里的所有人
On behalf of everyone here,
要求和威尔福德先生说话
I demand to speak to Mr. Wilford.
就是现在 梅兰妮
It's time, Melanie.
我是班尼特
This is Bennett.
抱歉 我需要你为我接通他的电话
I'm sorry. I need you to put me through to him.
很紧急
It's urgent.
我们又要再演一次吗
Oh, hey, are we doing this again?
谢谢 我等着
Thank you. I'll wait.
愿意做任何让你高兴的事
Anything to put a smile on your face.
威尔福德先生
Mr. Wilford.
首先是好消息
Good news first --
我们可能已经确认凶手了
we may have identified the killer.
这是真的吗
Is that for real?
还是说也是在演戏
Or is that part of the act?
是的 头等厢的一名保镖
Yeah, a bodyguard from First.
但是那家人不太愿意
But the family's reluctant
让你的警探进入车厢进行调查
to let your Detective in to investigate,
他们想要跟你说句话
and they would like a word.
换我也会气坏的
Well, that would piss me right off.
怒气冲冲
Huff, huff, huff.
福爵家族
The Folgers.
是他们的人
It's their man.
是的 莱拉·福爵 先生
Yes, Lilah Folger, sir.
我知道 但她强烈要求
I know, but she's demanding it.
很好
Very good.
为了调查 我们允许他进去
For the investigation, we will allow him in,
但条件是你要陪着他
but only if you accompany him.
威尔福德先生 向您道歉
Mr. Wilford, my apologies.
似乎事情都解决了
It seems everything is sorted.
我想你 梅
I miss you, Mel.
谢谢您
Thank you for that.
再见 先生
Goodbye, sir.
三十分钟
30 minutes.
开始吧
Here you go.
全世界屎尿都在这儿了
All the piss and shit left in the world.
-你会习惯这味道的 -快 快开始
- You get used to the smell. - Quick, let's go.
-又不是霍乱 -霍乱也不是很糟
- Just not the cholera. - Cholera's not so bad.
快 快点 开始吧
Come on, quick, let's go.
趁他们还没来
Before they get here.
递给我
Pass me that.
睡衣
Pajamas?
是的 已经是半夜了
Yeah, it's the middle of the night.
挺合适的 是吧
Kinda works, huh?
行了 搞快点
It's fine. Better hurry.
-好 -出发 快点
- Alright. - Let's go. Hurry up.
把那个给我
Pass it to me.
去吧
There you go.
祝你好运
Good luck.
他是要检查我们的全部家当吗
Is he going to go through all of our things?
要不要再给他点喝的
Should we offer him a drink?
不了 谢谢你小莱
No thanks, LJ.
他曾服役于第七海军陆战队
He was 7th Marines.
后来做了私人保镖
Then he worked private security.
还有什么其他情况吗
What else can you tell me about him?
我们是在冰封开始时雇佣他的
We hired him when the Freeze started
以保证全家人的安全 他也做到了
to keep our family safe, and he did.
他也救过我的命
And he saved my life.
怎么救的
How'd he do that?
那与这无关 小莱
That's not pertinent, LJ.
有人见过这个吗
Anybody seen this before?
这是什么
What is it?
那是把开盖刀
It's a J-Hook.
养蜂用的
Used for beekeeping.
怎么了 他给我看过 他说是他找到的
What? He showed it to me. He said he found it.
-在哪儿找到的 -不知道
- Where? - I don't know.
捡来的吧
Scrounging.
在以前的养蜂场吗
The old Apiary?
我们以前有养蜂
We used to keep bees
直到三年前的一次蜂群衰竭失调
until a colony collapse three years ago.
所有的蜂箱和其余物品都装箱了
They crated up all the extra hives and everything.
存放在仓库里
They're in storage.
那我们就得找到那个箱子
Well, we need to find which crate.
你能让提尔过来吗
Can you send Till?
我能看看吗
May I?
莱拉 我们去另一个房间
Lilah, let's us three go into the other room.
我们可以商讨一下对你们最有利的处理方式
We can position this in a way that's best for your family.
司闸员提尔
Brakeman Till.
乔茜
Josie.
你是怎...你从车尾出来了吗
How -- How did -- Are you out of the Tail?
先别问 好吗 没时间了
No questions, okay? There's no time.
你还在食品处理部门吗
Are you still in Food Processing?
在 但我只负责切割和装载能量棒
Yeah, but I just cut and load the bars.
我不能插手配料之类的
I don't have access to ingredients or anything.
我们不是想要这个
That's not what we need.
你知道莱顿出来了吗
Did you know that Layton's out?
知道 他们让他当警探
Yeah, they're using him as a detective.
有一个杀手逍遥法外
There's a killer loose up here.
原来是这样
That's what it was.
好 听着
Okay, look.
我们想让你跟他联系
We need you to make contact with him.
乔茜 如果他们抓到我
Josie, if they catch me --
你可能会被送回车尾 我知道
You could be sent back to the Tail. I know.
亲爱的 我懂
Honey, I get it.
你现在很健康
You're healthy now.
你活得像个人样
You live like a human being.
车尾需要你
The Tail needs you.
我们需要你
We need you.
车尾一心
One Tail.
谢谢你
Thank you.
看来埃里克并不是出生就有现在这么好的条件
Looks like Erik wasn't born into the nice life he had up here.
对 他的童年并不美好
Yeah, I don't think he had a very good childhood.
你觉得他能干出这种事吗
You think he was capable of something like this?
也许吧
Maybe.
反正他打退了那些
He sure wasted those rioters
在我来雪国列车的路上想抓我的暴徒
who tried to grab me on the way to Snowpiercer.
他就是在那时救了你的命吗
Is that when he saved your life?
他总开玩笑说自己冷血
He joked about being cold-blooded.
为大冰封而生
Born for the Freeze.
就算这真的是埃里克 那也不是我们的错
Even if this was Erik, it's not our fault.
没人说是
Nobody's saying that.
我都能想象到会有什么闲话了
Oh, I can just hear the track talk.
这么多年来 我们都知道
Over the years, we learned that
埃里克作为列兵 有做过一些事
as a private soldier, Erik did things.
这是他的使命
It's what he's for.
他不是变态杀手
Not psychotic murder.
不能让人以为我们庇护了一个禽兽
It can't come off like we have sheltered a monster.
埃里克有没有在你面前展示出过暴力或古怪的行为
Did Erik ever get aggressive or...weird with you?
你们在车尾真的看不到太阳吗
You guys really not get to see the sun in the Tail?
我们很多人七年没见过太阳了
Most of us haven't seen the sun in seven years.
你住在这里
How's that make you feel,
享受应有尽有的生活 感觉怎么样
living up here with everything you need?
是你们自己没有票
I mean, you guys didn't have tickets.
瞧好了
Watch this.
他问了你和埃里克的关系
He asked about your relationship with Erik.
那怎么了
What about it?
他会不会和你说什么
He tell you things?
让你保守秘密
Ask you to keep secrets?
小莱
LJ?
不 我最好不说
No, I-I better not talk about it.
我们能坐下谈谈吗
Can we sit?
我要问你们关于埃里克和小莱的事
I need to ask you about Erik and LJ.
我们等你的消息 好吗
We'll expect to hear from you, okay?
再见
Bye.
嗯
Yeah.
迈尔斯
Miles...
克里斯托弗
Oh, Christopher.
和妈妈说说 她会理解的
Talk to Mom. She'll understand.
随便了
Whatever.
她要迟到了
She's gonna be late.
伙计 你这样让我很紧张
Mate, you're stressing me out doing that.
两分钟
Two minutes.
-总算来了 -嗯
- 'bout time. - Yeah.
圣地亚哥要发心脏病了
Santiago here's about to have a heart attack.
我们得赶紧走 快点
We got to move. Faster.
穿上这个
Put this on.
好 好
Okay. Alright.
三 二
Three, two...
-好了 -一
- There you go. ... - one.
继续工作
Back to work.
嗯 继续工作
Yeah, back to work.
所以我们突然
So, suddenly we're searching for
要找一个拿手枪的专业士兵了
a professional soldier with a pistol?
.38左轮
Revolver .38.
真令人安心 谢谢
That's comforting, thank you.
你确定他没在上面吗
Hey, you sure it's not above?
不 就是在这层
No, it's on this level.
这边
Over here.
这里有人吗
Anybody in there?
开门
Open up.
他跑了
He's on the move!
他在上边
He's up top!
站住 站住
Stop! Stop!
上上上上
Go, go, go, go!
让开
Out of the way!
奥斯维勒 抓住他
Osweiller, get him!
我上去了
I'm going up!
他又下去了 他去楼梯了
He's going back down! He's going to the stairs!
好 我去追
Okay! I'm on it.
让开 让开
Move! Move!
小奥
Oz!
他要跑掉了
He's getting away!
快点
Go, go, go!
该死
Shit!
埃里克只能带两个包上车
Erik was only allowed two bags on the train,
然后他带了唱片
and he brings records.
都是他爸爸的
They were his dad's.
他恨他爸爸
He hated his dad.
他是白人
He was white.
还用说
Yeah, no shit.
是只猫
It's a cat.
我知道 只是
Yeah, yeah, I-I know. It's just...
有段时间没见过了
It's been a while.
也是埃里克救下来的
Erik saved him, too.
它从哪来的
Where'd he come from?
雪皮特是伪装大师
Snowpeter is a master of disguise.
雪皮特
Snowpeter?
真逗
That's funny.
我听说你们吃人
I hear you eat people.
现在不吃了
We put a stop to that.
为什么
Why?
这让前面的人都害怕你们
It keeps everyone up here scared of you.
我愿意为了让所有人惶恐不安而吃人
Like, I'd eat a dude just to make everyone shit bricks
就像他们害怕车尾人一样
like they do with the Tail.
我知道这首歌
I know this song.
妮基·吉奈特也知道
So did Nikki Genet.
你知道
You know,
你对抗这系统的时候
you're a lot cooler smashing the system
比你做威尔福德走狗时酷多了
than you are being Wilford's dick.
或许我们可以两者兼得
Well, maybe we can do both.
埃里克有跟你说过他用这个做过什么吗
Erik ever tell you what he did with this?
绝不可能
Never.
可以说埃里克养育了小莱
Erik practically raised LJ.
迟早会曝光的 莱拉
It's going to come out, Lilah.
-闭嘴 罗伯特 -不行
- Zip it, Robert. - We can't.
埃里克和小莱很亲密
Erik and LJ are close.
"亲密"
"Close."
我无法拒绝她
I can't say no to her.
在当下
It's these times.
道德品行就是个移动靶子
Morality's a moving target.
你开门了吗 安东
You open yet, Anton?
快来 珍珠 你来了
Come in, Jinju. You made it.
贝丝的礼物在这儿
I've got Bess' gift right here.
-拜托 -闭嘴 闭嘴
- Please... - Shut up. Shut up.
一把枪
A gun.
一把真枪
An actual gun.
安静
Keep quiet.
不然我就爆了你的头
Or this artifact will blow your head off.
好
Okay.
我们 我们不想惹麻烦
Okay, we're -- we don't want any trouble.
你知道他们不顾我反对
You know they hauled me up out of the Tail
把我从车尾拖出来破这案子吗
to solve this against my will?
这事跟我的利益无关
I got no skin in this game.
埃里克或许是凶手 但是移除身体部位
Erik might've been the murderer, but removing body parts --
他就是因为这个而搞砸了
that's how he screwed up.
你说搞砸是指什么
What do you mean he screwed up?
阉割是激情犯罪
Well, castration's a crime of passion.
一个女人惩罚男人的措施
A punishment that women lay down on men.
那不是他的主意 对吗
That wasn't his idea, was it?
他多半只是在帮他人
He's probably just controlling the victim
控制受害者 对吗
for somebody else, right?
我们要放你的歌吗
So, are we playing your song?
要是我是个蓝眼睛头等厢女孩
Shit, if I was a blue-eyed Firstie girl,
我也会想要拖延时间
I'd be playing for time, too.
埃里克会死得很壮烈 对吗
Erik's going down in a blaze of glory, right?
他不会进抽屉
He's not going to The Drawers.
没人说出去
So, no one tells.
而你终于能感觉到什么
And you finally got to feel something.
当他为你按住那些男人的时候
When he held those men down for you.
咔嚓
Chop, chop.
假设你说对了2%
Say you were even 2% right.
车尾人需要东西
Tailies need stuff.
总是在四处搜寻
Always scrounging.
你肯定想要设计图吧
Bet you'd like blueprints.
能要枪吗
How about guns?
只有头等厢安保人员有
Only First Class security gets those.
你是说真的
You really are serious.
但我打赌一个蓝眼睛头等厢女孩
But I bet a blue-eyed Firstie girl
或许能搞到枪
might be able to get her hands on one of those.
我只需要守口如瓶就行吗
And all I got to do is tell nobody?
他就在这里某个地方 我们在门口安排了守卫
He's somewhere in here. We got jackboots on the door.
好了 各位 我们要扩大封锁范围
Alright, folks, we're extending lockdown right now.
她说过会这样的
She said this was coming.
谁
Who?
你的女人吗
Your girl?
大家听好
Alright, folks, listen up.
照我说的做
Just do what I say...
跪下 快
Get down. Now.
刷芯片 刷芯片
Chip in. Chip in.
快点
Move!
下去 下去
Down. Down, go!
嫌疑犯在那
There's the suspect!
他在下面 有一个人质
He's down below, one hostage.
到我们这边来
Push down towards us.
快点
Go. Go.
告诉我你的名字
Just tell me your name.
这重要吗
Does that matter?
拜托了
Please.
他们来了
They're coming.
包抄
Alright, flank.
转过去
Turn around.
Turn around!
跪下
Kneel down.
向前
Forward!
不不 我们不能轻举妄动
No, no! We have -- We have to hold!
退后 他会开枪打她的
Hey, pull back. He'll shoot her.
放下棍子
Batons down!
把武器都放下 快
Weapons on the deck, now!
冲
Advance!
帮我接通梅兰妮·卡维尔 很紧急
Get me Melanie Cavill. It's urgent.
他死了
He's dead.
埃里克死了
Erik's dead?
我在呢 宝贝 我在
I got you, baby. I got you.
亲爱的
Sweetie.
没事的
It's okay.
有我在
I got you.
亲爱的
Oh, honey.
没事
It's okay.
什么情况
What's happening?
埃里克只是听命行事的走狗
Erik was a dog who did what he was told.
小莱拉叫他折磨
And Lilah Junior told him to torture
并杀害了两个三等厢乘客
and kill two Third Class men.
什么
What?
你女儿是杀人犯
Your daughter's a murderer.
-放肆 -什么
- How dare you! - What?!
不 不 小莱 不
No, no, LJ, no.
小莱 住手 不
LJ, stop it! No!
不
No!
不 不要 不
No! No! No! No! No!
放开我的宝贝
Leave my baby alone!
你立刻放开她
You get off of her right now!
所有乘客请注意
Attention all passengers.
我代表威尔福德先生
On behalf of Mr. Wilford,
与各位分享这一消息
I share this news --
曾藏匿于我们之中的谋杀犯已死
the murderer who hid among us is dead,
第二名嫌犯已被关押
and a second suspect is in custody.
多亏了成功的调查
Thanks to a successful investigation,
秩序得以恢复
order has been restored,
威尔福德先生向各位保证 正义必胜
and Mr. Wilford assures you justice will prevail.
威尔福德工业全体员工感谢你们
From all of us at Wilford Industries, thank you.
现在威尔福德先生必须伸张正义
Now Mr. Wilford has to deliver justice.
那承诺也是由你负责吗
You in charge of that promise, too?
不如我请你喝一杯 警探
How about I buy you a drink, Detective?
很美 不是吗
Beautiful, isn't it?
是的
Yeah.
人类统治和资源控制的纪念碑
A monument to human dominion and resource control.
好啦
Come on.
先把政治放一边 好好庆祝胜利
Let's put the politics down and celebrate a win.
我去 是清酒
Oh, shit. Sake.
你认为威尔福德先生的大秘密是什么
What do you think Mr. Wilford's big secret even was?
我只想回车尾 梅兰妮
I just want to go back to the Tail, Melanie.
你知道我不能放你回去
You know I can't let you do that.
你看见了太多
You've seen too much.
你已经想到了 莱顿
You figured it out, Layton.
我知道
I know you did.
神话具有强大的力量
A myth's a powerful thing.
希望你永远不知道它的重量
Pray you never know the weight of it.
对不起 莱顿
I'm sorry, Layton.
-谢谢 -注意保暖 兄弟
- Thank you. - Keep warm, brother.
等一下 等一下
Hang on. Hang on, mate.
好吧 里面没东西
Okay, nothing there.
给你
There you go, mate.
吉美
Yoshimi.
你一如既往地迷人
You're looking stunning as always.
什么...
What the --
太好了
Yes.
你替我
Take over.
-乔茜 -他在干什么
- Hey, Josie! - What's he doing?
让我过去
Coming through, guys.
小心碰头 让一让
Mind your head. Excuse me!
什么事
What is it?
看来阿斯特丽德兑现了承诺
Looks like Astrid came through.
-太好了 -是啊
- Yes. - Yeah.
莱顿失踪了
别登记他
Keep him off-book.
还有 医生
And, Doctor,
威尔福德先生不希望他受到损伤
Mr. Wilford does not want him damaged.